Jared Blumer

Pittsburgh, PA | jaredblumer@protonmail.com | jaredblumer.com | github.com/jaredblumer

Professional Summary

Results-driven Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience developing full stack web applications that serve millions of users. Experienced in designing resilient systems, automating deployments, and optimizing performance for high-traffic platforms.

Skills

Languages & Frameworks: React, TypeScript, Node.js, Python, Ruby on Rails DevOps & Infrastructure: Terraform, Docker, AWS, GitHub Actions, GitLab, Jenkins

Testing: React Testing Library, Jest, Cypress, Selenium, pytest, RSpec

Databases: GraphQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Professional Experience

Full Stack Developer, Pittsburgh Cultural Trust - Pittsburgh, PA

Oct 2024 - Present

- Managed and optimized AWS infrastructure (ECS, Fargate, EC2, RDS, S3, Lambda, CloudFront) with load-balanced multi-environment deployments, ensuring high availability and reliability for a platform serving 2.3M users.
- Engineered major CMS and e-commerce enhancements in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript, developing editorial tools (page previews, version history, page search) to improve publishing efficiency and customer-facing features (interactive seat maps, package purchasing flows, digital wallet integration) to improve the checkout experience for a platform generating \$23M annually.
- Implemented caching for high-traffic API endpoints, eliminating 2,400 redundant calls per day and improving "Add to Cart" flow performance by 25%, increasing checkout speed and reliability.

Software Engineer, NextLink Labs - Pittsburgh, PA

Nov 2021 – Nov 2023

- Engineered full stack features for a leading college-recruiting platform using React, TypeScript, Node.js, and Ruby on Rails, improving user experience for athletes and coaches on a platform with 4.3M annual profile views.
- Designed and developed a data analysis dashboard for healthcare research opportunities and patient demographics using React, TypeScript, and D3.js, streamlining oversight and reporting for \$150K in annual research funding.

Director, Data Analytics, The Eye & Ear Foundation of Pittsburgh – Pittsburgh, PA

June 2020 – Nov 2021

- Leveraged Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, Jupyter Notebook, Tableau, and SQL to analyze and visualize fundraising metrics and donor demographics, informing data-driven strategy for a 96,000-record constituent database.
- Designed database solutions for the Development Team to better cultivate prospects and donors for future giving, assisting a team of just seven in securing \$41.2M in donations.

Software Engineer, DAI Builds (Freelance) - Pittsburgh, PA

Dec 2018 - Jun 2020

- Developed full stack web applications leveraging topographical datasets and the Google Maps API to build dynamic, interactive map experiences using React, TypeScript, Node.js, and Python.
- Refactored client applications to address performance and accessibility issues, achieving 40% faster load times and full WCAG compliance.

Leadership and Open Source

Founder, Code & Coffee Pittsburgh

June 2019 - Present

• Organized an inclusive monthly meetup for Pittsburgh's developer community, creating space for learning, networking, and career growth in tech, with over 1,800 members.

Volunteer Technical Contributor, Wikimedia Foundation

June 2024 - Present

• Worked with Wikimedia's Quality and Testing Engineering Team to develop solutions for improved testing coverage of the MediaWiki platform, best known as the platform behind Wikipedia and related projects.

Education